Guide to the Yevgeny Yevtushenko Papers M1088
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Photographs, Series 7.
  - Subseries 2. Abroad
    - Abroad, 1970 - 1973; photographs (Box 48, Folder 4)
      England, 1971; Cyprus, 1972; USA, 1973; at the house of Rose Styron; Japan, 1972; Singapore, 1972; Malaysia, 1973.
      Peonides, Elli
    - Peru, 1971 (Box 48, Folder 5)
      With Val'carcel' [?]
    - Philippines, 1972; photographs (Box 48, Folder 6)
      Yevtushenko's birthday celebration in the Philippines, 1972; with poet Jose Garcia Villa.
      Garcia Villa, Jose; Avelino, Frank
    - Abroad, 1974 - 1975; photographs (Box 48, Folder 7)
      Yugoslavia, 1974; Poland, 1975.
      Rsumovic, Ljubivoje
    - Abroad, 1976 - 1979; photographs (Box 48, Folder 8)
      England, 1976; Italy, 1978; traveling along the Selenga (river) through Mongolia to Lake Baikal.
      Boyars, Arthur; Butler, Jan; Shinkarev, L.
    - Abroad, 1980 - 1985; photographs (Box 48, Folder 9)
      Ulan-Bator, Mongolia, 1980; Frankfurt, 1981; with German writer Bernt Engelmann, 1982; Japan, 1982; with poet Kim So Yzop [?], 52nd International PEN Congress, Korea, ca. 1984.
      Engelmann, Bernt; Stegenskii, Vladimir
    - Virginia, USA, 1980 (Box 48, Folder 10)
      With Israel Gutchin and Albert Todd in Virginia.
      Todd, Albert; Gutchin, Israel
    - Italy, 1984; photographs (Box 48, Folder 11)
      Meeting Nika Turbina and her grandmother at the aiport in Rome; Premio Internazionale Leone D'Oro, Venezia, 1984.
      Pascucci, Evelina; Turbina, Nika
    - Finland, 1986; photographs (Box 48, Folder 12)
      Helsinki, Tampere, Villa Annala; with great Finnish actor, Tarmo [?]
    - Sudan, 1986 (Box 48, Folder 13)
    - Abroad, 1986 - 1989 (Box 48, Folder 14)
      Peking, 1986; Heinrich Böll's grave; Boulder, CO, 1986; with Jim Ragan and Kirk Douglas in Venice, CA, 1987 May 2; with Ohela Halevy in NYC, 1988; Israel, 1988; Italy, 1988; Bangkok Exhibition, March 1988; Japan, 1989.
      Halevy, Ohela; Douglas, Kirk; Ragan, Jim
    - Prague, 1989 (Box 49, Folder 1)
      Opening of photo exhibit in Prague; Soviet ambassador Lomakin. Letter and pictures sent to Yevtushenko by Frantishek Chernogorski, Secretary of the Czechoslovak Union of Journalists.
      Lomakin,; Chernogorski, F.
    - Abroad, 1990 (Box 49, Folder 2)
      Mezhdunarodnyi poeticheskii konkurs, New York, 1990 Aug. 30; Booksigning in bookstore with Jim Ragan in La Jolla, CA
      Ragan, James
    - Abroad, 1991 - 1993 (Box 49, Folder 3)
      Cincinnati-Kharkov Sister Cities, Cincinnati Union Terminal, 1991; with German translator Godehard Schramm and his wife, 1991 - 92 Sept.; memorial "To the Victims of Faschism", Lvov, 1992; Booksigning in the USA, 1992; D.G. Willis Books, La Jolla, CA, with American poet Jim Ragan, 1993 May; Commencement Speech, Juniata College, USA, 1993; Bronx, 1993; St. Norbert College, De Pere, WI, 1993 Apr. 4; Des Moines, Iowa, 1993.
      Ragan, James; Schramm, Godehard
    - Abroad, 1994 - 1999 (Box 49, Folder 4)
      Calendar, Melbourne, Victoria, Australia, 1994; Wisconson with Professor Davidson, 1994; in the officer of the publisher "Liberty," NY, 1994; Israel, ca. 1994; in Australia with Geoffrey Dutton, 1995; with translator Vera Dunham in New York, 1995; Bronx, NY, 1997; with Birgitta Ingemanson and Susan Kilgore, WSU, Pullman, 1997 Mar. 8; El Paso, TX, 1997 Feb. 2; Indianapolis, 1997 Oct. 12; with American novelist and professor Lucy Ferris at Hamilton College, 1998 Mar. 4.
      Rosa, Eugene; Wiley, Jackson; Kilgore, Susan; Paul, Jess; Hayden, Michael; Ingemanson, Birgitta; Ferris, Lucy; Gerzon, Joan; Farlow, Lorelei; Farlow, Tom; Dunham, Vera; Dutton, Geoffrey; Beattle, Herbert; Wiley, Jane; Davidson,
    - Sofia, Bulgaria: Photo exhibit, undated (Box 49, Folder 5)
      At the opening of photo exhibit in Sofia; with Bulgarian poets Bozhidar Bozhilov and Georgi Djagarov; with poet Lyubomir Levchev and director of the publisher, the widow of Volodia Basheva; with Luben Georgiev and great Bulgarian poet Blaga Dimitrova.
      Djagarov, Georgi; Basheva, Vladimir; Dimitrova, Blaga; Bozhilov, Bozhidar; Georgiev, Luben; Levchev, Lyubomir
    - South Korea, undated (Box 49, Folder 6)
    - By country: Algiers - Puerto Rico, undated (Box 49, Folder 7)
      Algiers; house where Hitler was born and the grave of his parents, Austria; Australia; Burma; Canada; China; Cyprus with Elli and Panos Peonides; England; on Bernard Pivot's program "Apostrophe," Paris, France; with famous dissident Lev Kopelev in Germany; Laos; Netherlands; with Daisy Zamora, poet and Deputy Minister of Culture; in Puerto Rico with wife Maria (Masha) Yevtushenko.
      Peonides, Elli; Kopelev, Lev; Zamora, Daisy; Yevtushenko, Maria; Pivot, Bernard; Peonides, Panos
    - By country: Thailand - Yugoslavia, undated (Box 49, Folder 8)
      Thailand [?]; Yugoslavia.
    - By country: USA, undated (Box 49, Folder 9)
      Yevtushenko, Maria; Todd, Albert
    - USA: Florida, undated (Box 49, Folder 10)
    - Miscellaneous photos taken while traveling abroad [1 of 2], undated (Box 49, Folder 11)
    - Miscellaneous photos taken while traveling abroad [2 of 2], undated (Box 49, Folder 12)
    - USA, 1998; Accession 2004-022 (Box 106, Folder 3)
      Yevtushenko with his wife Masha, Albert Todd, students.
    - USA: Florida[?], undated; Accession 2004-022 (Box 106, Folder 4)
  - Subseries 3. Peformances
    - Performances, 1950 - 1959 (Box 50, Folder 1)
      Sad Baumana (Bauman Garden), Moscow, 1956; one of the first "Day of Poetry" in a bookstore, Moscow, ca. 1957.
    - Performances, 1960 (Box 50, Folder 2)
      Polytechnic museum; Khar'kov
    - Performances, 1961 - 1964 (Box 50, Folder 3)
      Polytechnic museum, (Okudzhava, Gladilin, Bokov), first recitation of "Babii Yar," Moscow, 1961; Park Kultury imeni Gor'kogo, 1961; Festival in Helsinki, 1962.
      Okudzhava, Bulat; Gladilin, Anatolii; Bokov,
    - Khar'kov, 1964 (Box 50, Folder 4)
      Performed at the store "Poeziia" on Pushkin Square.
    - Performances, 1965 - 1969 (Box 50, Folder 5)
      Portugal, 1966; Senegal, 1966; Baku, 1966; Tbilisi, 1968; performance in Chile attended by the Soviet Ambassador and hist wife, 1967; Mexico [?], Hall of Sports, 1967.
    - Kazan', 1969 - 1970 (Box 50, Folder 6)
      KGU (Kazan' State University)
    - Angarsk [?], 1970 - 1971 (Box 50, Folder 7)
    - Performances, 1970 - 1975 (Box 50, Folder 8)
      Minsk; Peru, 1971; Alma-ata, 1972.
    - Performances, 1976 (Box 50, Folder 9)
      Cheliabinsk; Magnitogorsk; Leningrad; Tbilisi; Moscow.
    - Performances, 1977 - 1979 (Box 50, Folder 10)
    - Performances, 1980 - 1985 (Box 50, Folder 11)
      Performing with Eduard Treskin in Kazan', 1982 (see also Photographs/General/1980 - 1985 [Box 45, Folder 10]); Toliatti, 1982 Mar. 14.
    - "Karavella", 1980 Nov. 24 (Box 50, Folder 12)
      Photocopies of typescript articles about the performance, 6 p., 1980 Nov.
    - Kazan', 1981 (Box 51, Folder 1)
      Reading of "Kazan'skii universitet"
    - Performances, 1986 (Box 51, Folder 2)
      University of Colorado, Boulder, 1986; PEN Club, New York City, 1986; Helsinki, Finland, 1986.
    - Performances, 1987 - 1989 (Box 51, Folder 3)
      Dvorets Sporta, stadiona imeni Lenina, Moscow, 1987; Moscow, 1988 Dec.; Chernovtsi, 1988.
    - Khar'kov, 1989 (Box 51, Folder 4)
    - Performances, 1990 - 1994 (Box 51, Folder 5)
      Leningrad, 1993; New York, 1992.
      Sobchak, A.
    - Performances, 1995 - 1999 (Box 51, Folder 6)
      Presentation of the book, "Samoe - samoe," Moscow, 1995.
    - Miscellaneous performances [1 of 12], undated (Box 51, Folder 7)
    - Miscellaneous performances [2 of 12], undated (Box 51, Folder 8)
      Lenin library; TsDL; among others.
    - Miscellaneous performances [3 of 12], undated (Box 51, Folder 9)
    - Miscellaneous performances [4 of 12], undated (Box 51, Folder 10)
    - Miscellaneous performances [5 of 12], undated (Box 51, Folder 11)
    - Miscellaneous performances [6 of 12], undated (Box 52, Folder 1)
    - Miscellaneous performances [7 of 12], undated (Box 52, Folder 2)
    - Miscellaneous performances [8 of 12], undated (Box 52, Folder 3)
    - Miscellaneous performances [9 of 12], undated (Box 52, Folder 4)
    - Miscellaneous performances [10 of 12], undated (Box 52, Folder 5)
      in USA with Jim Ragan.
    - Miscellaneous performances [11 of 12], undated (Box 52, Folder 6)
    - Miscellaneous performances [12 of 12], undated (Box 52, Folder 7)
    - Portraits, undated; Accession 2004-022 (Box 106, Folder 5)
  - Subseries 4. Portraits
    - Portraits, 1950 - 1965 (Box 52, Folder 8)
    - Portraits, 1966 - 1972 (Box 52, Folder 9)
      Playing hockey in Angarsk, ca. 1970; Peredelkino, 1972.
    - Portraits, 1973 - 1979 (Box 53, Folder 1)
      Tomsk, 1973; Bulgaria, 1977.
    - Portraits, 1980 - 1999 (Box 53, Folder 2)
      Sverdlova [?], 1981; Israel, 1988; Kazan', 1988 May; Moscow, 1988 Dec.; Khar'kov, 1989
    - Yevtushenko playing tennis, swimming, etc.: n.d., undated (Box 53, Folder 3)
      Koktebel'; Gul'ripshi; on the Black Sea.
    - Formal Portraits, 1950 - 1990 (Box 53, Folder 4)
      "Chto takoe rodina?", among others.
    - Formal Portraits[1 of 2], 1990 - 1999 (Box 53, Folder 5)
    - Formal Portraits[2 of 2], 1990 - 1999 (Box 53, Folder 6)
    - Portraits signed by Yevtushenko, undated (Box 53, Folder 7)
    - Slides, negatives, and positives, undated (Box 53, Folder 8)
    - Postcards and Calendars, undated (Box 53, Folder 9)
      Calendars commemorating Yevtushenko's 50th birthday, postcards.
    - Portraits[?] [1 of 2], 1950 - 1969 (Box 53, Folder 10)
    - Portraits[?] [2 of 2], 1950 - 1969 (Box 53, Folder 11)
    - Miscellaneous portraits [ 1 of 12], undated (Box 54, Folder 1)
    - Miscellaneous portraits [ 2 of 12], undated (Box 54, Folder 2)
    - Miscellaneous portraits [ 3 of 12], undated (Box 54, Folder 3)
    - Miscellaneous portraits [ 4 of 12], undated (Box 54, Folder 4)
    - Miscellaneous portraits [ 5 of 12], undated (Box 54, Folder 5)
    - Miscellaneous portraits [ 6 of 12], undated (Box 54, Folder 6)
    - Miscellaneous portraits [ 7 of 12], undated (Box 54, Folder 7)
    - Miscellaneous portraits [ 8 of 12], undated (Box 54, Folder 8)
    - Miscellaneous portraits [ 9 of 12], undated (Box 54, Folder 9)
    - Miscellaneous portraits [10 of 12], undated (Box 55, Folder 1)
    - Miscellaneous portraits [11 of 12], undated (Box 55, Folder 2)
    - Miscellaneous portraits [12 of 12], undated (Box 55, Folder 3)
    - Legal-size, 1989 (Box 65, Folder 2)
      Includes a portrait to Yevtushenko from Sorokinoi, L.V. [?], 1989 May 12.
    - Miscellaneous Oversized [1 of 2], undated; photographs (Box 80, Folder 7)
    - Miscellaneous Oversized [2 of 2], undated; photographs (Box 80, Folder 8)
    - Chernovtsi, 1988 Jan. 4; photographs (Box 80, Folder 9)
      Numerous pictures pasted together in one frame.
    - "O radosti bytiia" by A. Gor'kov, undated; photograph (Box 80, Folder 10)
      Gor'kov, A.
    - Portraits Taken by Alex Gotfrid, undated; Accession 2004-022 (Box 106, Folder 6)
  - Subseries 5. Works
    - Bratskaia GES, undated (Box 55, Folder 4)
    - Detskii Sad: Film Fragments [1 of 2], 1983 (Box 55, Folder 5)
    - Detskii Sad: Film Fragments [2 of 2], 1983 (Box 55, Folder 6)
    - Detskii Sad: Photos with negatives, 1983 (Box 55, Folder 7)
    - Detskii Sad: Photos with writing on the back, 1983 (Box 55, Folder 8)
    - Detskii Sad [1 of 8], 1983 (Box 55, Folder 9)
    - Detskii Sad [2 of 8], 1983 (Box 56, Folder 1)
    - Detskii Sad [3 of 8], 1983 (Box 56, Folder 2)
    - Detskii Sad [4 of 8], 1983 (Box 56, Folder 3)
    - Detskii Sad [5 of 8], 1983 (Box 56, Folder 4)
    - Detskii Sad [6 of 8], 1983 (Box 56, Folder 5)
    - Detskii Sad [7 of 8], 1983 (Box 56, Folder 6)
    - Detskii Sad [8 of 8], 1983 (Box 56, Folder 7)
    - Detskii Sad: Pictures of Yevtushenko, 1983 (Box 56, Folder 8)
    - Detskii Sad: Scenes, 1983 (Box 56, Folder 9)
    - Detskii Sad: Formal Pictures, 1983 (Box 56, Folder 10)
    - Konets Mushketerov: Proby na rol' d'Artan'iana v TsDL s angliiskimi studentami (Tryouts for the role of d'Artagnan at TsDL with English students), undated (Box 57, Folder 1)
    - Mama i neutronnaia bomba (in Lithuania), undated (Box 57, Folder 2)
    - Pokhorony Stalina, undated (Box 57, Folder 3)
      Redgrave, Vanessa; Todd, Albert
    - Pozdnye Slezy: Bookjacket negatives, undated (Box 57, Folder 4)
    - Pod kozhei statui svobody, undated (Box 57, Folder 5)
    - Vzlet (Takeoff) [1 of 2], 1979 (Box 57, Folder 6)
      Includes pictures of the banquet after the premiere at TsDL.
      Kadochnikova, Larisa; Kulish, Savva; Rosi, Francesco; Bondarchuk, S. F.; Chikirev, M.
    - Vzlet (Takeoff) [2 of 2], 1979 (Box 57, Folder 7)
  - Subseries 6. Family & Friends
    - Ancestors and more distant relatives, undated (Box 57, Folder 8)
      Relatives in Belarus; grandfather; grandmother; uncle, among others. Photograph of commentary to picture album of Irina Rudolfovna Kozintsova (Tetia Ra).
      Dubinin, Andrei; Gangnus, A.R.; Gangnus, Irina; Gartwig, Ivan; Yevtushenko, Yermolay
    - Zinaida Ermolaevna Yevtushenko [Yevtushenko's mother] [1 of 3], undated (Box 57, Folder 9)
    - Zinaida Ermolaevna Yevtushenko [Yevtushenko's mother] [2 of 3], undated (Box 57, Folder 10)
    - Zinaida Ermolaevna Yevtushenko [Yevtushenko's mother] [3 of 3], undated (Box 57, Folder 11)
    - Elena Yevtushenko (sister), undated (Box 57, Folder 12)
    - Photos and postcards belonging to Zinaida Yevtushenko [1 of 2], undated (Box 58, Folder 1)
    - Photos and postcards belonging to Zinaida Yevtushenko [2 of 2], undated (Box 58, Folder 2)
    - Family pictures of Yevtushenko, undated (Box 58, Folder 3)
      Includes photo of maternity hospital where Yevtushenko was born.
    - Bella Akhmadulina [1st wife of Yevtushenko], undated (Box 58, Folder 4)
    - Galina Semenovna Sokol (Galia) [2nd wife of Yevtushenko], undated (Box 58, Folder 5)
      Yevtushenko, Peter; Yevtushenko, Galina
    - Petr Yevtushenko (Petia) (Yevtushenko's oldest son, son of Galina Semenovna) [1 of 2], undated (Box 58, Folder 6)
    - Petr Yevtushenko (Petia) (Yevtushenko's oldest son, son of Galina Semenovna) [2 of 2], undated (Box 58, Folder 7)
    - Petr Yevtushenko (Petia) [1 of 2], 1976 (Box 58, Folder 8)
      Includes photos of trips to Cheliabinsk and Magnitogorsk.
    - Petr Yevtushenko (Petia)[2 of 2], 1976 (Box 58, Folder 9)
    - Jan Butler (3rd wife of Yevtushenko) [1 of 2], undated (Box 58, Folder 10)
    - Jan Butler (3rd wife of Yevtushenko) [2 of 2], undated (Box 59, Folder 1)
    - Aleksandr Yevtushenko (Sasha) [2nd son, mother - Jan Butler], undated (Box 59, Folder 2)
    - Anton Yevtushenko (Tosha) [3rd son, mother - Jan Butler], undated (Box 59, Folder 3)
    - Jan Butler, Sasha, Tosha, Petia, undated (Box 59, Folder 4)
      Butler, Jan; Yevtushenko, Peter; Yevtushenko, Yevgeny Aleksandrovich; Yevtushenko, Anton
    - Orthodox Wedding Ceremony to Maria Novika, Philadelphia:, 1991 (Box 59, Folder 5)
    - Wedding Reception: Philadelphia, 1991 (Box 59, Folder 6)
    - Maria Yevtushenko (Masha) (4th wife) and sons (Mitia and Zhenia), undated (Box 59, Folder 7)
      Toast by the poet Andrei Voznesenskii on the day after wedding to Masha, 1988 Jan. 1. Stephen Cohen and Nina Bouis as guests in New York apartment, 1992
      Cohen, Stephen; Yevtushenko, Dimitri; Bouis, Nina; Yevtushenko, Yevgeny Aleksandrovich; Voznesenskīĭ, Andreĭ; Yevtushenko, Maria
    - All five sons, 1992 (Box 59, Folder 8)
      Yevtushenko, Peter; Yevtushenko, Yevgeny Aleksandrovich; Yevtushenko, Dimitri; Yevtushenko, Yevgeny Aleksandrovich; Yevtushenko, Anton
    - Miscellaneous relatives, undated (Box 59, Folder 9)
    - Negatives, undated (Box 59, Folder 10)
    - Proofs, undated (Box 59, Folder 11)
    - Slides, undated (Box 59, Folder 12)
    - Friends: A - M, undated (Box 60, Folder 1)
      Zommar, Edik; Chernykh, Vladimir; Bouis, Sasha; Turbina, Nika; Bouis, Nina; Milo, E.; Besser, Gedalia; Milner-Gulland, Robin; Bernause, William D.; Dubinin, Andrei; Aranas, Frank; Allen, Joy; Kennedy, Edward; Laskina, E.; Harris, Svetlana; Korzhenovekov, Tefik; Gutchin, Israel; Korzavin, Naum; Gedin, Per; Koriakin, Igor; Gedin, Brigitte; Milner-Gulland, Hal; Ellis, Royston; Milner-Gulland, Alison; Lugovsky, M.; Creegh, John Patrick; Levi, Peter
    - Castro, Fidel, 1960 (Box 60, Folder 2)
      Castro, Fidel
    - Chichibabin, Boris (poet), 1989 (Box 60, Folder 3)
      Kharkov, 1989.
    - Dutton, Geoffrey and family, undated (Box 60, Folder 4)
      With children Sam, Frances, and Tisi, and wife Nin.
      Lucas, Robin; Dutton, Geoffrey
    - Franco, Dora (Colombian model), undated (Box 60, Folder 5)
      Franco, Dora
    - Kazakov, Iurii, undated (Box 60, Folder 6)
      Kazakov, Iu.
    - Friends: N - Z, undated (Box 60, Folder 7)
      Booklet with picture and signature of Robert Rozhdestvenskii.
      Okudzhava, Bulat; Rozhdestvenskii, Robert; Norton, Boyd; Nunn, Ancel; Shostakovich, Dmitriéi Dmitrie; Sard, Hannah (Kapilla); Shatalinin,
    - Padilla, Heberto [Cuban poet], undated (Box 60, Folder 8)
      with Georgian poet Tamaz Chiladze.
      Chiladze, Otar; Padilla, Heberto; Yevtushenko, Galina; Chiladze, Tamaz; Padilla, Berta
    - Ragan, James and family, undated (Box 60, Folder 9)
      With friends Bill and Muriel Gaddis, Sofia, 1986 Nov. 30; wife Debora, daughters Tera and Mara, and son Jameson Jon.
    - Smoktunovskii, Innokentii, 1990 Jan. 1 (Box 60, Folder 10)
      In Peredelkino on the day after the wedding, 1990 Jan. 1.
      Smoktunovskii, Innokentii
    - Todd, Albert and family (Box 60, Folder 11)
      Daughter Lara Todd.
    - Tselkov, Oleg [artist] (Box 60, Folder 12)
      Balakini, G.; Tselkov, Oleg; Shchukin, V.
    - Vasil'ev, Iurii (Box 60, Folder 13)
      artist
    - Miscellaneous pictures of friends [1 of 3] (Box 60, Folder 14)
      Kopelev, Lev
    - Miscellaneous pictures of friends [2 of 3] (Box 60, Folder 15)
    - Miscellaneous pictures of friends [3 of 3] (Box 60, Folder 16)
      Khrushchev, N.
    - Art and other pictures (Box 60, Folder 17)
      "Pamiatnik zhertvam fashizm L'vovskogo getto;" Vid" Tomska; sculpture
    - Postcards (Box 60, Folder 18)
      Several postcards of photographs by Allen Ginsberg, include pictures of Peter Orlovsky, Jack Kerouac, William Burroughs, Gregory Corso, Paul Bowles.
      Koonen, A.G.; Izvitskaia, Izol'da; Ginsberg, Allen; Andreev, Vladimir
    - Funeral, undated (Box 65, Folder 3)
      Participants in the demonstration and funeral of the victim, L. P. Afazhaev [?].
    - Zinaida Ermolaevna Yevtushenko: Legal-size, 1928 - 1931 (Box 65, Folder 4)
      A. P. Baianova's class at the tekhnikum, including Zinaida Yevtushenko, 1928. Tsentral'noe biuro iach. VLKSM, Geologo-Razvedochnogo Instituta Moskva, 1930 - 1931 (includes Zinaida Yevtushenko).
    - Franco, Dora (legal-size), 1968 (Box 65, Folder 5)
      Two portraits.
    - Zinaida Ermolaevna Yevtushenko (oversized), 1939; photographs (Box 80, Folder 5)
      Muzykal'noe uchilishche, vypusk, 1939.
    - Unidentified Portrait, 1995; Accession 2004-022 (Box 106, Folder 7)
    - Yevtushenko with his Son, undated; Accession 2004-022 (Box 106, Folder 8)
    - Yevtushenko with his Son, undated; Accession 2004-022 (Box 106, Folder 8)
  - Subseries 7. Photographs taken by Yevtushenko
    - [6 of 14] (Box 62, Folder 1)
    - Photographs (Box 61, Folder 1)
      Japan; Campuchea; Italy; Mongolia.
      Butler, Jan; Dutton, Geoffrey; Martini, Helene
    - Photographs with negatives (Box 61, Folder 2)
      Uzbekistan, Hong Kong, Japan, Singapore.
    - Negatives (Box 61, Folder 3)
    - Slides [1 of 2] (Box 61, Folder 4)
    - Slides [2 of 2] (Box 61, Folder 5)
  - Subseries 8. Unidentified photographs
    - [1 of 14] (Box 61, Folder 6)
    - [2 of 14] (Box 61, Folder 7)
    - [3 of 14] (Box 61, Folder 8)
    - [4 of 14] (Box 61, Folder 9)
    - [5 of 14] (Box 61, Folder 10)
    - [6 of 14] (Box 62, Folder 1)
    - [7 of 14] (Box 62, Folder 2)
    - [8 of 14] (Box 62, Folder 3)
    - [9 of 14] (Box 62, Folder 4)
    - [10 of 14] (Box 62, Folder 5)
    - [11 of 14] (Box 62, Folder 6)
    - [12 of 14] (Box 62, Folder 7)
    - [13 of 14] (Box 62, Folder 8)
      Novyi Mir.
    - [14 of 14] (Box 62, Folder 9)
    - Moscow Architecture (Box 62, Folder 10)
    - Legal-size (Box 65, Folder 6)
      Latin America, Alma-Ata.
    - Oversized, undated; photographs (Box 80, Folder 6)
  - Subseries 9. Photograph albums
    - Performance at Moscow State University, 1963 Dec. 14 (Box 63, Folder 1)
    - Performance:, 1974 Oct. 14 (Box 63, Folder 2)
    - Bratskaia GES, 1977 (Box 63, Folder 3)
      "in the name of the 50th Anniversary of Great October"
    - Performance in Kazakhstan, 1977 Mar. 24 (Box 63, Folder 4)
    - Argentina, 1984 (Box 63, Folder 5)
      10a. Exposición EL LIBRO Del Autor Al Lector
    - Performance in Russia, 1986 Jan. 19 (Box 63, Folder 6)
      "Vystuplenie poeta E. Yevtushenko pered lichnym sostavom trizhdy ordenonosnoi divizii im. F. Dzherzhinskogo MVD SSSR"
    - Israel, 1988 Dec. (Box 63, Folder 7)
    - Russia, 1987 - 1988 (Box 63, Folder 8)
      "Neskol'ko dnei iz zhizni Yevgeniia i Mashi Yevtushenko" by A.G. Levinoi and V. Sozinova
    - Undated photograph albums [1 of 2] (Box 63, Folder 9)
      Thailand [?], photo exhibit in Chernovtsi; China; another unidentified album.
    - Undated photograph albums [2 of 2] (Box 63, Folder 10)
      Two albums, one of Asia [?] and one of Central Asia [?].
    - Vzlet (Takeoff), 1979 (Box 64, Folder 1)
    - REN-TV: "Poet v Rossii bol'she, chem poet", 1997 (Box 64, Folder 2)
    - Photographic Exhibition "Shadows and Faces," Bangkok, 1988 Mar. 12 - 15 (Box 65, Folder 1)
      Includes newspaper clippings.
      Valkov, Anatoli
    - Pictures Taken by Yevtushenko, undated; photographs in an album (Box 79, Folder 1)
    - Large Album [1 of 2], undated; photographs in an album (Box 79, Folder 2)
      Includes Yevtushenko speaking in Khar'kov in 1989; at the premier of the film "Romeo and Juliet;" at the premier of "Pod kozhei statui svobody;" performance at museum in Donetsk, 1983 Jan. 22; Irkutsk, 1975; filming "Detskii Sad," 1983; Germany with wife Galina, 1963.
    - Large Album [2 of 2], undated; photographs in an album (Box 79, Folder 3)
      Includes Peredelkino, 1972; opening of photo exhibition in Vilnius; Irkutsk, 1973 Sept. 3; Lena River, 1965; Khar'kov, 1989; Harvey Smith in Hotel Breslin, 1985 Jan. 12, New York City, signed by Allen Ginsberg, given to Yevtushenko 1986 Feb. 17; pictures from the filming of "Vzlet;" Peredelkino, 1987.
      Butler, Jan; Ginsberg, Allen; Tselkov, Oleg; Yevtushenko, Peter
    - Latvia: 1967 (Box 82, Folder 1)
    - Life [1 of 2], 1966 (Box 82, Folder 2)
    - Life [2 of 2], undated (Box 82, Folder 3)
      Includes pictures from Latin American trip in the sixties.
- Audiovisual Materials, Series 8.
  136 videotapes. Approximately half are of Yevtushenko's REN-TV series "A Poet in Russia is More than a Poet." The rest are primarily amateur quality tapes of his poetry readings at various universities.
  - REN-TV: 1. Vstupitel'naia peredachak programme "Poet v Rossii bol'she, chem poet"; 2. Satiriki - diadia Giliai, O. Chiumina, Lazarev-Gruzinskii, V. Umanov-Kaplunovskii, Brikhnichev, Viatkin, A. Amfiteatrov, A. Nozdrin, Kazantsev, 1 videocassette of 1 (VHS); sd. col.; 1/2 in. NTSC format (Box 66, Folder 1)
    Lazarev-Gruzinskii; Kazantsev; Nozdrin; Chiumina; Umanov-Kaplunovskii; Brikhnichev; Viatkin; Amfiteatrov
  - REN-TV: 1. K. Sluchevskii, V. Shchirovskii; 2. I. Bunin; 3. M. Voloshin; 4. K. Bal'mont, A. Belyi; 5. I. Annenskii, V. Sologub, 1 videocassette of 1 (VHS); sd. col.; 1/2 in. NTSC format (Box 66, Folder 2)